Alexandra Buczek

PhD Candidate

Enthusiastic data scientist, skilled in research and communication. As a PhD Candidate, utilized both Python and R to organize and clean data, run statistical analyses, and visualize results. Experienced in academic research and communication to both academic and general audiences

Work History

2016-09 -Current

PhD Candidate

American Museum Of Natural History, New York, NY

- Cleaned and organized data using Python pandas and numpy
- Utilized ordination and statistical analyses in R and Python
- Visualized data and results using R ggplot2 and Python matplotlib and seaborn
- Employed Jupyter Notebooks for enhanced accessibility and sharing of coding pipelines
- Communicated methodology, results, and implications of research via public presentations and published academic papers

2018-09 -2018-12

Adjunct Professor

Hunter College, New York, NY

- Taught CSci 127 Introduction to Computer Science lab section, providing instruction to up to 30 undergraduate students
- Instructed students using discussions and demonstrations in Python and C++

2018-07 -2018-12

Teacher and Content Expert

AMNH Lang Science Program, New York, NY

- Created lectures and planned learning activities to facilitate understanding of scientific method for up to 20 high school students
- Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to facilitate and moderate classroom discussions and student centered learning
- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional approaches and innovative classroom activities.
- Implemented and encouraged debate-style classroom environment to increase student engagement and promote critical thinking

Education

2016-09 -Current

Ph.D.: Comparative Biology

American Museum of Natural History - Richard Gilder Graduate School - New York, NY

2012-09 -2016-05 Bachelor of Science: Geology-Biology

Brown University - Providence, RI

Contact

Address

New York, NY, 10011

Phone

(860) 986-3805

E-mail

buczeka94@gmail.com

LinkedIr

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandra-buczek-4a27a

WWW

https://ajbuczek.github.io/

Skills

Data Cleaning

Very Good

MS Office

Excellent

Organization

Excellent

Technical writing

Excellent

Data collection and analysis

Very Good

R

Good

Python

Very Good

Data visualizations

Very Good

Languages

Spanish

Polish

••••